All right. Moving on to customer sophistication.
I think this is the best way to show off different sophistication levels when it
comes to buyers and shoppers.
And from a low sophistication level, you have Walmart.
If you're from a different country, Walmart is, you know, it's, it's, it's mass.
Everyone has been to Walmart here in America, and there's,
Walmarts are like very popular in the Midwest. Um, and then you,
you move up a notch and you go to, to Target, which is medium sophistication.
You got a lot of moms here. Um, you know, they have a lot higher quality stuff,
um, more fashionable things. And you can get clothing, you can get everything.
You, you, you can get at Walmart, but it's just a little nicer.
It's a little nicer. And then you move on to high sophistication.
You got Sax fifth Avenue, which is premium stuff. You go in there,
you look at the price tags, you just like lose your mind. So as you can see,
there's a different level of sophistication, even when you go into the store,
what it looks like, what it feels like, the, the pricing of the products,
the brands that they carry. Uh, and as you move up,
it gets narrower and narrower. Um, you know, you're not offering everything,
uh, that you would at Walmart.
And even Target has like their own brand of stuff,
their brand of clothing and their brand of, of home goods, right?
And as you move up, not to say that Sax Fifth is a department store or like a,
a shopping store where you get groceries and whatnot,
but we're talking about expensive luxury clothing.
And so you go in there and everything is dialed in from the customer
service to the quality, to the smell, to the lights,
to the decoration.
It's a completely different experience going from Sacks fifth to Walmart.
Here's another example of low sophistication people versus
high sophistication people. Guys, this is, and I I,
I'm adding this disclaimer at the very bottom. This is a spectrum,
and by no means an absolute measure of the quality of a person.
You could be low sophistication in terms of, of,
of this and be a great person. You could be highly sophisticated and be a jerk,
okay? And you could be the other way around. Um, there's no,
there's no perfect answer here.
I'm just letting you know from like a general standpoint, okay?
'cause I worked with a brand that had a lower sophistication audience. And,
um, you're dealing with people from the Midwest and, uh, who,
who weren't very complex with, you know, with the, with themselves who,
who weren't very tech savvy. And, um, not to say that they're,
they're bad people or anything. Not at all. They're beautiful, beautifully, um,
nice people and friendly. Um, you just have different upbringings.
And so this is, this is gonna affect how you present your,
your brand and your product and your advert and your video to the audience,
okay? 'cause someone with a high sophistication isn't gonna buy from a low
sophistication product or, or store. And, and vice versa.
Someone with low sophistication isn't gonna buy from a high sophistication
store. No. It's just, it's not gonna work.
So I've broken down really quickly what that means,
or at least from my own words. Um, I would say lowest sophistication people,
they can, they're concerned about price and they really want a deal.
They care about deals, higher sophistication. They care about quality,
and they're willing to pay for that quality.
'cause they prefer longevity and lifetime of, of, of their products.
Um, lower sophistication, lower class income. You know, they,
they meet a different, um, income bracket versus higher sophistication.
They're middle to elite class income. All right? You've got the,
the multimillionaires in there. Lower sophistication,
no formal education versus formal education or self-taught
lower sophistication. You have the working class, even unemployed, uh,
versus professionals and business owners,
I would say in the higher sophistication, lower sophistication, easier to sell,
higher sophistication, harder to sell. I guess this is, this could be argued.
Um, anyone could be easier or difficult to sell,
just depends on their background. But, um,
it comes down to how you're presenting the message, right? It, it,
it, I'll break down some examples,
but you're not gonna sell a lower sophistication product to a higher
sophistication person. High, highly sophisticated person, and vice, vice versa.
It just doesn't make sense. Here's an example of like two different stores.
You got low sophistication and high sophistication.
If you've ever been to a 99 cent store, everything there is a dollar. Okay?
You go in there, the products are cheap, quality, everything's a dollar,
the place is a mess. It's, um, you see things that are expired.
You're like, what is going on in here? Um,
and the demographic in that place is typically people who, you know, who,
who are unemployed, or I'm not gonna say all of them,
but there's definitely a lower income, uh, type person in there, all right?
Versus if you go into a whole foods that place is, is dressed up to the nines,
everything is way overpriced,
but everything is very high quality and they have so much to offer in terms of
variety. And you've got a very sophisticated looking person, uh, who, who,
who shops there, uh, higher income level. And, um, it, it's a lot more to,
I would say, manage, um, from an,
from an appearance side and as well as a product quality side.
So those are very two different places to, to be in.
Ask, ask yourself how sophisticated is your customer? It's very important to,
to know your,
your customer's sophistication because it's gonna affect how you actually do
your marketing. You gotta take into account your product, you know, the product.
I would say the branding of the product too. Your, the box,
the directions, all of that. The customer experience is gonna be very,
very important depending on the sophistication level of your audience.
If they're low sophistication level,
they're not really gonna care as much how they're presented with the box or the
product. This is why dropshippers can get away with so much, you know,
so much junk is because it's just, you know, they're, they're not,
they're not marketing to the rich, to the rich and elite.
They're marketing to the lower brackets. Another thing is price.
If it's too high, they're not gonna buy. If it's too low, they're gonna be like,
this is cheap. Your website, very, very, very important.
If it's like very gimmicky, crappy looking site, it's not gonna,
you're gonna repel higher sophisticated people,
low lo if it's a crappy site, lower sophisticated people,
they're not gonna tell the difference. Okay? In creative,
are you gonna do like a drop shippy style,
or are you gonna do a very branded approach? Are you gonna do very, like,
clean and very dyna or very, um, what's the word,
commercial looking. Um, and then brand and mission, right? These are two things.
I, I would say as a drop shipping brand,
you don't really have a mission or a brand, but if you're CareAway, that, uh,
kitchen set brand and mission are gonna be very, very important.
And you're gonna appeal to the, the more sophisticated audience.
Okay? So I believe that wraps up module five.
Thank you so much for watching it, and I will see you in the next one.
Hope you enjoyed it.